Register of the Japan, Koshikan (Korea) records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Documents relating to the granting of passports, (Meiji 42-nen ryoken kafu ni kansuru shorui), 1909; 58 frames.
  Illegible frames: 15, 19, 21. Each frame is also numbered 1349. 32a, 33b contain tables.
- Documents relating to Koreans abroad, (Meiji 42-nen zaigai Senjin kankei), 1909; 66 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 380.
  Documents relating to Koreans abroad and their activities. Feb. 5 - Nov. 8, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 1334. 34b, 66b contain tables. 34a in English.
- Documents relating to Chinese [residents in Korea], (Meiji 42-nen Shinkokujin kankei), 1909; 13 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 381.
  Confidential correspondence between Resident-General Sone and Japanese Foreign Minister Komura relating to the maintenance of Antung-Mukden railroad. Aug. 3-23, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 1333.
- English-language memorandum, (Meiji 42-nen Eibun oboegaki), 1909; 3 frames. (Reel 17)
  Box/Folder 7: 382.
  "List of foreigners employed by the Korean government" giving the name and the date, and the terms of the contract.
  Illegible frame: 3. Each frame is also numbered 1323. All in English.
- Documents relating to matters handled by the Department of Foreign Affairs [of the Residency-General], (Meiji 39, 40-nen Gaimubu toriatsukai), 1906 - 1907; 98 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 383.
  A list of cases handled by the Department of Foreign Affairs of the Residency-General, 1906 - 1907.
- Documents relating to foreigners, (Meiji 39, 40-nen gaikokujin), 1906 - 1907; 14 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 384.
  Documents relating to the land and other property owned by foreigners in Korea. Jan. 27 - Apr. 1, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 1318. 6b contains a map.
- Secret documents relating to Japanese nationals [in Korea] and Yi Ik-ho and another person, (Meiji 39-42-nen honpojin kimitsu oyobi Ri Yokko hoka ichimei kankei), 1906 - 1909; 42 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 385.
  Secret reports of Japanese Police Inspectors-General of Korean Police Maruyama Shigetoshi and Wakabayashi Raizo, and of Chief of Korean Police Bureau Matsui Shigeru relating to political speeches made by Japanese newspaper reporters in Korea; anti-Japanese activities of the members of the Tae Han Hy0phoe party (Korea Association); and Yi Ik-ho, a Korean captured by the Russians during the Russo-Japanese War. Apr. 23, 1908 - Mar. 22, 1910.
  Each frame is also numbered 1319. 33, 34, 41b in Korean.
- Documents relating to the inspection of the Yalu and Hun river valleys and the collection of taxes from fishermen, (Meiji 40, 42-nen O, Kon ryoko ryuiki shisatsu oyobi gyomin chozei), 1907 and 1909; 107 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 386.
  Documents relating to the imposition of taxes upon Korean fishermen by the Chinese government. Jan. 29, 1909. An inspection report on the Yalu and the Hun river valleys. Sept. 7, 1907.
  Illegible frames: 12, 29b, 52a, 70, 71b, 72a, 88-97, 102, 105-107. Each frame is also numbered 1337. 17, 18, 19b-24 contain maps. 90-95a contain tables.
- Documents relating to foreign settlements, (Meiji 39, 42-nen kakkoku kyoryu kankei), 1906 and 1909; 30 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 387.
  Texts of regulations and other documents relating to the establishment of Chinese settlements at Inchon, Pusan, and W0nsan. Mar. 11 - Dec. 13, 1909.
  Illegible frames: 13b, 17, 20a. Each frame is also numbered 1317.
- Documents relating to Russian-leased territory in Masan, (Meiji 42-nen Masan Rokoku soshakuchi kankei), 1909; 47 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 388.
  Documents relating to the purchase by the Japanese of the land formerly leased by the Russians from the Korean government in Masan. Texts of the land lease agreement between Korea and Russia signed on May 22, 1900. Mar. 8 - May 12; 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 1321. 39, 40 in English; 43-47 in Korean.
- Documents relating to [Japanese] residents who rendered meritorious service during the war of (Meiji 38-nen 37, 8-nen sen'eki koro kyoryusha kankei), 1904-1905; 13 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 390.
  Documents relating to the commendation of Japanese residents in Korea who rendered meritorious service during the Russo-Japanese War. Jan. 29, 1909 - Apr. 25, 1913.
  Each frame is also numbered 1359.
- Confidential letters relating to various matters, (Meiji 40-nen hisho zakken), 1907; 174 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 392.
  Confidential correspondence between Resident-General Ito and Deputy Resident-General Sone relating to the affairs of Min Yong-ik and the French adviser to the Korean Emperor, E. Martel; and popular uprising in Korea. A letter from Korean Prime Minister Yi Wan-young to Ito relating to Min Yong-ik. Records of conversations between Yi Wan-yong and Ito concerning Korean political problems. Confidential correspondence of Ito with Japanese Prime Minister Saionji and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayshi Tadasu relating to Crown Prince Yi Un; Emperor Sunjong's reform program and the reactions of Korean political leaders to this program; Russo-Japanese relations; and the return of Pak Y0ng-hyo to Korea. Mar. 24 - Dec. 23, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 1670. 37b, 38a, 50b, 51a, 53b in Korean.
- Summaries of newspaper and magazine articles, (Meiji 42-nen shimbun zasshi kiji tekiyo), 1909; 66 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 393.
  Survey of newspapers and magazines published in Korea, and outstanding political articles which appeared in various society publications in 1909.
  Illegible frames: 11, 29, 48. Each frame is also numbered 1709.
- Documents handled during the Deputy Resident-General's stay in Tokyo (Meiji 42-nen taikyochu toriatsukai shorui, fukutokan jokyochu), 28 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 394.
  Correspondence between Resident-General Ito and Deputy Resident-General Sone during the latter's stay in Tokyo relating to the changes in the Korean cabinet and the increase in the budget and personnel of the Japanese gendarmerie. June 6 - 20, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 1682.
- Miscellaneous documents, (Meiji 41-nen zakken), 1908; 24 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 395.
  Confidential reports submitted by the Japanese Inspector-General of the Korean police to Resident-General Ito relating to the financial affairs of the Korean court. Feb. 5 - 22, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 1683.
- File of miscellaneous documents, (Meiji 41-nen zakken tsuzuri), 1908; 26 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 396.
  Reports of Chief of the Korean Police Bureau Matsui Shigeru submitted to Resident-General Ito and others relating to the political activity of Yi [UNK]-guk and his publications directed against the Ilchin'hoe party. Oct. 21 - Dec. 11, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 1684.
- Documents relating to An Chung-gun and the union of two countries, (Meiji 42-nen An Jukon oyobi gappo ni kansuru shorui), 1909; 301 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 397.
  Confidential reports of the Japanese gendarmerie relating to the anti-Japanese political activity of Kim Sang-gun and his associates; the trial records of An Chung-gun's brothers An Ch0ng-gun and An Kong-gun, and others. Oct. 5, 1909 - Apr. 27, 1910.
  Each frame is also numbered 1717. Two different frames numbered 113. 91a contains a diagram. 92a in Korean.
- Plans for the implementation of large-scale pacification in South Korea in (Meiji 42-nen Nankan daitobatsu jisshi keikaku sonota), 1909; 115 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 398.
  Summary of a speech by the Japanese Chief Public Procurator Kokubu Sangai at the provincial police chiefs' conference relating to police administration in Korea. Documents relating to a plot to overthrow the Korean government and to assassinate the cabinet ministers (includes a list of conspirators). Mar. 17, 1907 - Aug. 14, 1910.
  Missing frame: 111. Illegible fr.: 16b, 17a, 41a. Each frame is also numbered 1719. 16b, 17a, 41a, 45, 46a contain maps. 10b-12, 21b-24, 29b, 30a, 39b, 40, 43b-45a, 52b, 63b-65 contain tables.
- Documents relating to the Prince Ito disaster in (Meiji 42-nen Ito Ko sonan ni kansuru shorui), 1909; 257 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 399.
  Confidential reports of Japanese Police Inspector-General of Korean police Wakabayashi Raizo submitted to Resident-General Sone relating to the death of Prince Ito; records of police investigation of An Ch'ang-ho, Ch0ng Tae-ho, and other suspects; anti-Japanese organizations in Korea; and reaction among the Koreans regarding the death of Ito. Oct. 27 - Nov. 13, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 1718. 185-187a contain tables.
- Minutes of conferences on the improvement of the administration of Korea, (Meiji 39-nen Kankoku shisei kaizen (e) [ni] kan (han) [suru] kyogikai hikki), 1906; 495 frames.
  Box/Folder 7: 400.
  Minutes of fifteen joint conferences of the Korean government and the Japanese Residency-General regarding the administrative reorganization and political, economic, and social reforms in Korea. Mar. 13, 1906 - May 4, 1907.
  Missing frame: 121. Illegible fr:. 50. Each frame is also numbered 1658.
- Reports on the suppression of the Tonghak Rebellion, (Meiji 27-nen Togakuto seito ni kansuru shohokoku), (1894-4) 1894; 358 frames. (Folder 1)
  Instructions and reports concerning the suppression of the Tonghak Rebellion in the North and South Ch'ungeh'0ng Provinces, Hwanghae, South Ky0ngsang, and South Ch0lla Provinces.
- Correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts, - Part I (Meiji 30-nen kakkan ofuku jo), 1897; 3 frames. (Folder 45)
- Copies of Japanese-language telegrams to and from the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 33, 34-men wabun dempo ofuku hikae), 1900-1901; 132 frames. (Folder 65)
- Confidential correspondence received from the Masan Consulate, (Meiji 33-nen kimitsu Masan ryojikan raishin), (1900-5) 1900; 297 frames. (Folder 84)
  Documents relating to financial arrangements for the purchase of land in the foreign settlement at Masan; the arrival of a Russian warship in Masan; Korean-Russian negotiations for the purchase of land for a military base in Masan; the discovery of copper on Kojedo Island; revision of the territorial arrangements on W[UNK]olly[UNK]ongdo Island (near Masan) between Japan and Russia; the employment of foreign engineers by the Korean government; the exchange of Japanese-leased land in Yulkumi and Russian leased land on W0lly0ngdo Island; the increase in the annual rent for the land leased by the foreigners in Masan outside the foreign settlement; and the [UNK] students in Japan.
- Correspondence to and from the Home Office, (Meiji 33-nen honsho oraishin), (1900-8) 1900; 57 frames. (Folder 85)
  Documents relating to the extension of the period of payment for a Japanese loan; Japanese-Korean postal agreement; the Seoul-Inchon R.R.; Korean railroad regulations; Korean laws concerning the foreigners for defamation of national honor; educational problems; and popular uprisings in the P'y0ng'an and Hwanghae Provinces.
- Documents relating to Yi Chun-yong, (Meiji 28-32-nen Ri Shuny0 kankei shorui), (1905-36) 1895-1900; 96 frames. (Folder 91)
- Copies of confidential European-language telegrams of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Home Office and with other diplomatic posts, (Meiji 33-nen kimitsu honsho sonota obun ofuku den hikae), (1900-2) 1900; 89 frames. (Folder 94)
- Copies of confidential European-language telegrams of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Home Office and with other diplomatic posts, (Meiji 33-nen kimitsu honsho sonota obun ofuku den hikae), (1900-3) 1900; 51 frames. (Folder 95)
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Masan Consulate, (Meiji 34-nen Masan ryojikan kimitsu ofuku), (1901-5) 1901; 73 frames. (Folder 100)
  Confidential correspondence between the Japanese Minister in Korea and the Japanese consul in Masan relating to the activity of Russian warships in Chin'hae Bay; Russian request for a naval base in Chin'hae Bay; Japanese military facilities in Masan and Chabokp'o areas; Russian plan for the installation of submarine cables between Yulkumi and Masan; the opening of Unggi and Iji; Russo-Japanese relations in Korea; and the arrival of Russian Chargé d'Affaires in Masan.
- Confidential correspondence received from the Home Office, (Meiji 34-nen honsho kimitsu raishin), (1901-7) 1901; 104 frames. (Folder 101)
  Confidential correspondence received from the Home Office, relating to the conversations exchanged between the Japanese Minister in Russia Komura Jutaro and the Russian Minister of Finance; the attitude of foreign representatives in Tokyo toward the Korean and Manchurian problems; the Iby0ng uprisings in the Ky0ngsang Provinces; special instructions concerning Russian activities in Korea; French interests in Korea; the issue of one yen notes in Korea by the First Bank of Tokyo; and Pak Che-sun's mission to Japan.
- Correspondence received from various [Japanese] consulates [in Koreal], (Meiji 34-nen kaku ryojikan raishin), (1901-6) 1901; 69 frames. (Folder 103)
  Reports from Japanese consuls submitted to the Japanese Minister in Korea relating to the clash between Korean Catholics and other Korean residents on Chejudo Island; Russian troops and Russian coal dumps in Yulkumi; the arrival of a Norwegian steamer; and political and social conditions in the Kilchu and S0ngjin areas.
- Telegrams sent to the Home Office, (Honsho o den), (1903-2) 1903; 212 frames. (Folder 138)
- Correspondence received from [Japanese] consulates [in Korea], (Meiji 36-nen kakkan raishin), (1903-21) 1903; 8 frames. (Folder 146)
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Korean Court, etc. (Meiji 36-nen kyutei oyobi shoho ofuku), (1903-16) 1903; 38 frames. (Folder 147)
  Documents relating to the promotion of friendship between Korea and Japan; collection of taxes in the Naktong River area; and personal harm inflicted upon Japanese residents by the Koreans.
- Miscellaneous file of European-language [documents], (Meiji 36-nen obun zassan), (1903-15) 1903; 41 frames. (Folder 149)
- Miscellaneous documents, (Meiji 36-nen zakken), (1903-17) 1903; 45 frames. (Folder 150)
  Documents relating to the deterioration of Russo-Japanese relations, and the opening of Yong'amp'o.
- Japanese-Korean secret agreement and Korean neutrality, (Meiji-36-nen Nikkan mitsuyaku fu Kankoku churitsu), (1903-7) 1903; 58 frames. (Folder 151)
  Documents relating to the secret Japanese-Korean treaty; reports on political conditions in Korea; Japanese policy in Korea and China in connection with Russo-Japanese relations; and the question of Korean neutrality.
- Documents relating to the employment and resignation of Japanese advisers [in Korea], (Meiji 26-36-nen komonkan shintai oyobi hompojin kohei), (1894-21) 1894-1903; 131 frames. (Folder 154)
- Japanese-Korean agreement on loans and the adoption of a new system of weights and measures, (Meiji 34-36-nen Nikkan shakkan oyobi doryoko shakkan), (1901-18) 1901-03; 113 frames. (Folder 155)
  Documents relating to the establishment of the Korean Central Bank and the Bank of Seoul; negotiations for a 3,000,000 yen loan from the First Bank of Tokyo and J.M. Brown's opinion; the issue of banknotes in Korea by the First Bank; and the adoption of a new system of weights and measures.
- Correspondence received from the Korean government, -- Part I (Meiji 37-nen Gaibu rai - 1), (1904-5) 1904; 58 frames. (Folder 159)
- Documents relating to the development of uncultivated land, (Meiji 37-nen mikochi keiei), (1904-6) 1904; 228 frames. (Folder 161)
- Telegrams sent to the Home Office - Part I. (Den honsho o - 1), (1904-2); 240 frames. (Folder 162)
- Ditto -- Part II, (1904-2); 240 frames. (Frames numbered from 241-480) (Folder 163)
- Ditto--Part III, (1904-2); 282 frames. (Frames numbered 481-762.) (Folder 164)
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Army and Navy [Ministries], (Meiji 37-nen rikkaigun ofuku), (1904-12) 1904; 114 frames. (Folder 165)
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Korean Court, (Meiji 37-nen kyutei ofuku), (1904-4) 1904; 72 frames. (Folder 166)
- Japanese-Korean Protocol, (Meiji 36-nen Nikkan giteisho), (1903-20) 1903; 175 frames. (Folder 167)
  Documents relating to the Japanese-Korean Protocol signed on February 23, 1904 between Japanese Minister to Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Korean Acting Foreign Minister Yi Chi-yong.
- Telegrams received from the Home Office, - Part I (Meiji 37-nen den honsho rai - 1), (1904-15) 1905; 96 frames. (Folder 168)
- Ditto -- Part II, (1904-15); 144 frames. (Frames numbered 97-240.) (Folder 169)
- Documents relating to the Seoul-Pusan Railroad, (Meiji 37-nen Keifu tetsudo ikken shorui), (1904-24) 1904; 249 frames. (Folder 172)
- Confidential correspondence received from the Home Office, (Meiji 37-nen kimitsu honsho rai), (1904-11) 1904; 150 frames. (Folder 174)
- Confidential correspondence to and from the Japanese consular posts [in Korea], (Meiji 37-nen kimitsu kakkanofuku), (1904-8) 1904; 38 frames. (Folder 178)
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Japanese consulates in Chinnamp'o, Pyongyang, and Shin'iju, (Meiji 37-nen Chin, Hei, Gi den orai), (1904-20) 1904; 18 frames. (Folder 180)
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Japanese consulates in Masan, Pusan, and Mokp'o, (Meiji 37-nen Masan, Fuzan, Moppo orai), (1904-10) 1904; 27 frames. (Folder 181)
- Correspondence to and from the Home Office, (Meiji 37-nen honsho orai), (1904-3) 1904; 80 frames. (Folder 183)
- Documents relating to the Japanese-Korean Protocol of 1904 and the Russian and Korean ministers, (Meiji 37-nen Nikkan kyoyaku oyobi Ro-Kan koshi kankei), (1904-7) 1904; 103 frames. (Folder 184)
- Correspondence to and from the Japanese consulates in Chinnamp'o, P'y0ngyang, Shin'iju, W0nsan, and S0ngjin (Meiji 37-nen Chin, Hei, Gi, Gen, Jo orai), (1904-25); 57 frames. (Folder 185)
- Official correspondence with the Korean government; appendix - documents relating to Korean nationals, (Meiji 37-nen Kankan ofuku fu Kanjin kankei), (1904-9) 1904; 111 frames. (Folder 186)
- Copies of European-language telegrams received from the Home Office and other diplomatic posts, (Meiji 37-nen honsho sonota obun dempo raishin), (1904-16); 91 frames. (Folder 190)
- Copies of European-language telegrams received and sent by the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 37-nen obun dempo orai hikae), (1904-18) 1904; 89 frames. (Folder 191)
- Documents relating to the Russo-Japanese War and decorations awarded to Koreans, (Meiji 38-nen Nichi-Ro sen'eki kankei shorui Kanjin jokun), (1905-29) 1905; 101 frames. (Folder 191)
- Documents relating to military and private railroads, (Meiji 38-nen gun'yo tetsudo fu shisetsu tetsudo), (1904-24) 1905; 107 frames. (Folder 193)
- Documents relating to the Japanese management of the Korean communications system, (Meiji 38-nen tsushin kikan itaku toriatsukaisho), (1905-8) 1905; 83 frames. (Folder 195)
- Confidential correspondence received from the Home Office, (Meiji 38-nen honsho rai kimitsu), (1905-34) 1905; 47 frames. (Folder 197)
- Confidential correspondence to and from the Home Office, (Meiji 38-nen honsho ofuku kimitsu), (1905-15) 1905; 84 frames. (Folder 198)
- Documents relating to the Japanese management of the Korean communications system and the record of conversations between a high Chinese official and Minister Uchida concerning the Russo-Japanese War situation, (Meiji 38-nen Kankoku tsushin kikan toriatsukaisho oyobi Nichi-Ro senkyoku ni kanshi Shinkoku taikan to Uchida koshi kaidan), (1905-14) 1905; 11 frames. (Folder 199)
- Miscellany, (Meiji 38-nen zatsu), (1905-13) 1905; 19 frames. (Folder 200)
- Documents relating to the secret decree of the Korean Emperor and contract, (Meiji 38-nen Kankoku kotei mitchoku oyobi keiyaku), (1905-6) 1905; 94 frames. (Folder 201)
- Documents relating to foreigners employed [by the Korean government], (Meiji 38-nen yatoi gaikokujin), (1905-20) 1905; 149 frames. (Folder 202)
- Documents relating to the Russo-Japanese Peace Treaty, (Meiji 38-nen Nichi-Ro kowa joyaku), (1905-19] 1905; 161 frames. (Folder 203)
- Miscellaneous documents, (Meiji 38-nendo zakken), (1905-13) 1905; 86 frames. (Folder 204)
- Documents relating to the defendants in connection with the incident involving police advisers, (Meiji 38-nen komon keisatsu jiko hikoku), (1905-17) 1905; 124 frames. (Folder 205)
- Telegrams to and from the Home Office, -- Part IV (Meiji 38-nen honsho oraiden), (1905-12) 1905; 121 frames. (Folder 207)
- Ditto -- Part II, (1905-1); 142 frames. (Folder 208)
- Ditto -- Part III, (1905-1); 142 frames. (Folder 209)
- Documents relating to the Seoul Electric Company and special concessions relating to the water supply system, (Meiji 38-nen Keijo Denki Kaisha fu suido tokkyo), (1905-2) 1905; 389 frames. (Folder 210)
- Confidential correspondence sent to the Home Office, -- Part II (Meiji 38-nen honsho o kimitsu - 2), (1905-15) 1905; 120 frames. (Folder 211)
- Documents relating to police reform, (Meiji 38-nen keimu kaizen), (1905-5) 1905; 43 frames. (Folder 213)
- Correspondence sent to the Home Office, (Meiji 38-nen honsho o), (1905-16) 1905; 105 frames. (Folder 215)
- Telegrams received from the Home Office, (Meiji 38-nen honsho raiden), (1905-22) 1905; 132 frames. (Folder 217)
- Correspondence received from the Home Office, (Meiji 38-nen honsho rai), (1905-22) 1905; 4 frames. (Folder 218)
- Correspondence to and from the Japanese consulates in Pusan and Masan, (Meiji 38-nen Fuzan Masan orai), (1905-25) 1905; 8 frames. (Folder 220)
- Correspondence received from the Korean government, -- Part I (Meiji 38-nen Gaibu rai - 1), (1905-3) 1905; 8 frames. (Folder 221)
- Ditto -- Part II, (1905-3); 12 frames. (Folder 222)
- Ditto -- Part III, (1905-3); 11 frames. (Folder 223)
- Correspondence to and from the Japanese consulate at Inchon, (Meiji 38-nen Jinsen orai), (1905-28) 1905; 13 frames. (Folder 225)
- Correspondence with the Japanese consulates in Seoul and Inchon, -- Part II (Meiji 38-nen Keijo Jinsen orai - 2), (1905-11) 1905; 9 frames. (Folder 227)
- Confidential correspondence sent to Japanese consulate in Korea, (1905-4) (Meiji 38-nen kakkan o kimitsu) 1905; 4 frames. (Folder 228)
- Confidential correspondence from Japanese consulates in Korea, (Meiji 38-nen kakkan rai kimitsu), 1905; 42 frames. (Folder 229)
- Confidential correspondence received from Japanese consulates in Korea, (Meiji 38-nen kakkan rai kimitsu), (1905-4) 1905; 49 frames. (Folder 230)
- Correspondence sent to the Korean government, (Meiji 38-nen Gaibu o), (1905-18) 1905; 29 frames. (Folder 231)
- Ditto -- Part II, (1905-18); 22 frames. (Folder 232)
- Ditto -- Part III, (1905-18); 15 frames. (Folder 233)
- Correspondence with the Korean Court, (Meiji 38-nen kyuchu ofuku), (1905-9) 1905; 17 frames. (Folder 234)
- European-language telegrams received and sent by the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 38-nen obun dempo ofuku), (1905-30) 1905; 42 frames. (Folder 235)
- Correspondence with the Korean Court, (Meiji 38-nen Kankyu ofuku), (1905-27) 1905; 10 frames. (Folder 237)
- Correspondence with the Korean Court, (Meiji 38-nen Kankyu ofuku), (1905-27) 1905; 8 frames. (Folder 238)
- Correspondence to and from the Japanese consulates in Chinnamp'o and Pyongyang, (Chinnampo Heijo orai), (1905-26) 1905; 7 frames. (Folder 239)
- Correspondence between the Japanese Army Commander and the Chief of the Japanese Gendarmerie, -- Part II (Meiji 38-nen Gunken orai - 2), (1905-7) 1905; 20 frames. (Folder 242)
- Telegrams sent by the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Oden juichigatsu - sangatsu), (1905-31) Nov. 1905 - Mar. 1906; 54 frames. (Folder 244)
- Copies of telegrams sent by the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 39-nen denso hikaetsuzuri), (1906-2) 1906; 19 frames. (Folder 245)
- Copies of telegrams sent by the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 39-nen hasso denshin hikae), (1905-32) 1906; 8 frames. (Folder 247)
- Documents relating to Ch'0ngjin, (Meiji 37-nen Seishin kankei), 1904; 121 frames. (Folder 258)